

07946 538 191 barryhalper@gmail.com www.barryhalper.com www.github.com/barryhalper ♀



PROFILE

I am a highly motivated full-stack web developer and technical architect with over twenty years experience delivering market-leading business-to-business brands. I have extensive experience in web development, dev ops, cloud and database architecture, web design, SEO, server/domain management, cloud native infrasctruture (AWS) and cyber secuirty. As a technical lead, I have experience in team building, managing developers, determining project requirements, liaising with both internal and external clients to deliver projects that increase profits, and drive efficiency.



EXPERIENCE

Depertment Levelling Up Housing and Comminuties 2020-2023 SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELER (Energy Performance of Building Register)

Civil servant with SC clearance. Part of a multi disciplinary agile team delivering government infrastrcuture via kanban, trunck based development, TTD, code pairing and code review. As as a cloud practioner I played a key role in migrating our service to AWS with miminal downtime. I arhcitected cloud infrastructure incluing containerisation, CICD pipelines, data migration solutions all of which passed rigourous government penetrarion tesing and cyber security regiurements. I run reularly learining sessions on clean architecture, TTD and containerisation. Contribute to regulalar show and tell accross government. Acheived higest possible level qualification within the DDAT framework.

Hemming Group Ltd 2000-2020 WEB DEVELOPMENT MANAGER

Fulfilling the roles of application architect, technical lead and DBA I was responsibe for creating and managing a range business applications, CRMs, CMS and REST APIs for the



EDUCATION

M.A. Literature, Culture & Modernity University of London 1996-1998

B.A.(hons) English Literature & History (2:1) Manchester University 1990 -1993

Greenhill College, Harrow3 A Levels & 6 GCE'S (including maths & english) 1987-1990



SKILLS

ASP NET Framework/Core (C#) MVC, Web Forms, REST API, Entity Framework, LinqToSQL, Ruby, Bash, Docker, Terraform, Clean architecture, TTD (Rspec), Coldfusion Enterprise Server, Verity, Fusebox, CFscript, Javascript ES5 & ES6, JQuery, JSON, Babel, HTML 5, CSS 3, Bootstrap, XML, XSD, MS IIS, MS Windows Server, DNS management, MSSQL Servevr Server, Postgress T-SQL, PSQL MongoDB, Eclipse, Subversion, Tortoise SVN, Git, Web services Restful APIs, SOAP, Postman, CORS, Photoshop, MS Access applications (VB), ecommerce, Stripe, Worldpay Mark down

publishing and events business.

I implemented innovations in data storage, ecommce, publising and customer fullfilment systems. I upgraded the development platform (CF to .NET) and help stear the business towards iterative development using the latest web technologies/frameworks, UX standards and SEO best practices. As a manger I helped created the Hemming web team of three developers, a designer and a project manager.

SENIOR DEVELOPER 2005-2008

Responsible for hiring and managing a team of developers to delivery web solutions for the publishing business.e,g the development of a business wide CMS, used to publish localgov content (and its sister titles) on a in single paltform. I successfullly deilvered directory and data sales web applications for the local government sector by generating significate revenues. I implemented code standards, naming convetions and frameworks (fusebox) for the team. Provisioned hosting company.

WEB DEVELOPER 2005-2003

Created many websites for the enitre publising business inclduing "Lingerie Buyer" and "Company clothing" I created intranet applications for email marketing and subscription fullfillment using Coldfusion and Sql Server. I introduced ecommce to the business through Worldpay intergration and implmented Gooogle Analytics for all sites.

EDITOR 2003-2002

RESEARCH & DEVELOPMENT ASSITANT 2000-2001

Company Clothing 1998-2000 RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Hammicks Legal Bookshop 1994-1995 HEAD OF SUBSCRIPTIONS

Blackwells bookshop 1993-1994 BOOKSELLER

Freelance Web Developer 1998-2005



TRAINING COURSES

Building Data Solutions Using AWS Redshift 2023

Developing with AWS 2022 Architecting on AWS 2022 Terraform with AWS 2021 Getting started with Docker 2021

Testing Ruby with RSpec: The Complete Guide

2020

Ruby on Rails - A Jumpstart for .NET Developers 2020

Angular JS 2017

ASP.NET Programming in C# 2009
The Newly appointed manager 2006

Time Management 2005

Search Engine Optimisation Best Pratice 2004

Advanced Coldfusion 2004

MS Project 2003

Dreamweaver Ultradev 2001 Introduction to Coldfusion 2001 MS Access and SQL 2001



HOBBIES

Guitar player with my own you tub channgel
I am passionate about good food and regularly
cook for friends and family
I keep fit by regular walking and swimming
I am fascinated by history both modern and ancient
I like to discover new places and have travelled
widely

I speak a little Japanese